赛车运动的物流统筹是所有运动中最有挑战性的
No sport is as logistically challenging as motorsports.
诚然在所有运动中设备都很重要
While equipment matters in any sport,
但在赛车中 人只能算是半个运动员
in motorsports the human is only half the athlete
而车是另一半
—the vehicle is the other half.
赛车的性能直接取决于在正确的时间正确的地点有没有正确的零件
The performance of a motorsports vehicle is directly tied to having the right components
in the right place at the right time
所以其背后的物流统筹也是比赛的一部分
so the logistics are part of the competition.
赛车是一项运动 但也不全是娱乐 游戏之类
Racing may be a sport but it's not all fun and games.
因为车队都是商业化的——意思是要恰饭的
Teams are businesses—businesses that are expected to make money.
价值最高的F1车队——法拉利车队——值13亿美元
The most valuable Formula 1 team—Scuderia Ferrari—is worth over $1.3 billion.
单一个车队就和Discord  Bird Rides  DoorDash这些科技公司等值
This means this team is valued at about as much as tech companies Discord, Bird Rides, or DoorDash.
像法拉利这样有钱的车队可以在运输上花更多的钱
The wealthier teams, like Ferrari, are able to spend more money on transport
带更多设备和备件 当发生意外的时候容错性更高
to bring more equipment and spare parts which can make the difference between winning and losing when things go wrong.
F1赛事从各种方面来讲都是最具全球性的竞技赛事
Formula 1 is by many measures the most international sports competition.
每年21场比赛 车队们要在最短一周内频繁来往五大洲
Over its 21 yearly races the teams traverse five continents with as little as a week between events.
每年都有无数卡车 船只 飞机参与这场赛事的运输物流工作
A chaotic ballet of trucks, boats, and planes transports this show across the world each year.
参加F1的有10支车队
Ten teams compete in Formula 1,
尽管比赛遍布全球 但其仍属于欧洲的赛事
and despite it taking place worldwide it is by all measures a European sport.
10支车队中8支是在欧洲注册并运营的
Eight of the ten teams are registered in and operate out of Europe.
只有印度和美国的车队不在欧洲 但印度的车队基地在英国
Only the Indian and American teams are from elsewhere although, the Indian team is actually based in the UK
美国的车队基地在北卡罗来纳 但在英国还有第二基地在运营
while the US team, based in North Carolina, operates a secondary forward base in the UK
以便于在欧洲比赛时员工不必在美国和欧洲来回跑
so that its staff doesn't have to travel all the way back to the US between each of the European races
而最近几年欧洲的比赛几乎是连续的
which in recent years have been held consecutively,
除了大约在赛季中的夏天要去加拿大
with the brief interruption of the Canadian Grand Prix, in the middle of the season over summer.
也多亏如此 相比于其他地点 在欧洲的比赛物流统筹上更容易一些
Thanks to this, the European leg of the season is, compared to the rest, relatively easy logistically
因为你可以开欧卡
because within Europe you can drive.
卡车运输的费用比空运低多了
The cost of shipping by truck is so comparatively low to shipping by plane
车队们可以带着一整个"房子"满欧洲跑
that teams bring whole buildings with them to the European races.
这些房子类似人们常说的"房车"
These buildings are what are modestly referred to as "motorhomes"
但也能像红牛车队的三层结构那么大
but can be as large as Red Bull's three story structure
里面包括办公室 休息室 配有完整厨房的餐厅
that includes offices, bars, and a restaurant with a complete kitchen.
这些房子可以打包进几辆卡车中 并可以在两天内组装完成
All of that packs into a number of trucks and can be assembled in less than two days.
这些房子会和其他赛车 备件 电子设备等一同
Along with all the other equipment including cars, spare parts, and electronics,
由每个车队的数十辆卡车在欧洲大陆之间穿梭
convoys of dozens of trucks per team criss cross the continent before each European race.
正常来讲 比赛的正赛会在每两周的周日进行
Typically races are held every two weekends on Sunday
可以给车队们在大奖赛开始的周四之前足够的准备时间
which gives teams plenty of time to relocate before activity begins on the Thursday before the Grand Prix
但偶尔也会有例外 比赛会在连续的两个周末"背靠背"进行
but from time to time the schedule is crunched and races take place two weekends in a row.
这对车队的物流统筹就是很大的挑战 因为车队们只有三天时间收工
This proves a more daunting logistical challenge as teams only have three full days to break down,
运输 在新地点重新安装设备
transport, and reassemble their equipment at the new race site.
更要命的是 在2018年首次出现连续三个周末"背靠背靠背"的比赛日
Even worse, for the first time ever the 2018 season saw three weekends with three races in a row.
在6月24日法国大奖赛在法国的勒卡斯特雷进行
On June 24 the French Grand Prix took place in Le Castellet
随后下周来到了奥地利的史匹尔堡
then the next weekend the Austrian one was held in Spielberg
再下周来到了英国银石赛道
finishing off the following weekend with the British Grand Prix in Silverstone.
奥地利到英国的运输是最困难的 卡车要开近1000英里
1600公里
The Austria-UK transfer was the most difficult one as it involved driving nearly 1,000 miles
其中还要穿越英吉利海峡隧道
including through the choke-point of the channel tunnel.
在这趟运输中 每辆卡车由三名司机驾驶
For this trek, each truck was manned by three drivers
一人开 另外两人在后面的房车中睡觉
so that while one drove the others could sleep in an RV that accompanied the convoy.
这样卡车除了半路加油外可以不间断行驶
That way, the trucks could drive continuously only stopping to refuel.
但别忘了 这些物流统筹都是相比于海外赛事来说更容易的
But again, these races are easy logistically compared to the ones outside of Europe
海外赛事更难
—the ones known as flyaway races.
就像很多欧洲赛事一样 多数海外赛事也是两周一次
Just like with the European races the majority of flyaway races occur with two weeks between them
但偶尔也会有连续两个周末在相隔上千英里的两地"背靠背"办赛的情况
but from time to time races are scheduled on back to back weekends thousands of miles apart.
这些"背靠背"的海外赛事是F1赛季中物流统筹难度最大的
These back to back flyaway races are the most logistically difficult weeks of the Formula 1 season.
在2018年4月8日周日 巴林大奖赛在巴林萨基尔进行
On Sunday April 8th, 2018 the Bahrain Grand Prix was held in Sakhir, Bahrain
七天后的下一个周末 中国大奖赛在中国上海进行
then seven days later, the following weekend, the Chinese Grand Prix was held in Shanghai, China.
6400公里
两个赛道相距超过4000英里
Over 4,000 miles separated those two racetracks and yet,
而且和之前一样 一切都要在巴林周日晚上收工
just like with every race, everything came down on Sunday night in Bahrain
并在中国周四早上重新搭建完成
and had to be operational by Thursday morning in China.
更惨的是 上海与巴林有五小时时差 相当于干活时间少了5小时
Even worse, Shanghai is five hours ahead of Bahrain which is effectively five hours fewer to do the work
但实际上 这场运输的计划早在数月前就开始了
but in reality, the planning for this transfer began months before.
大约在2018年一月 当年赛季揭幕战开始前三个月
Around January 2018, three months before the first races of the season,
10支车队都会打包好5套集装箱
each of the ten teams packed up five sets of shipping containers.
每一套都有他们海外装备 比如桌椅 电器 厨具和车辆相关工具
Each of these sets held their sea kits carrying things like chairs, tables, appliances,
cooking utensils, and some elements of their garages.
这些大型 不那么贵重的货物走的是海运
They send these bulkier and less expensive pieces of equipment by sea
因为海运比空运便宜到不知道哪里去了
as it's massively less expensive than sending them by plane.
每组集装箱的具体数量由车队钱包决定 比如红牛就会多一点
The number of containers per team varies as the wealthier teams like Red Bull will take more
但平均下来每个车队会带三个40英尺的集装箱
but in general each team takes about three 40 foot containers.
诚然海运非常慢
Of course ocean shipping is slower,
但总共有五套 所以总会有一套在正确时间出现在正确地点
but since there are five sets there is always one at the right place at the right time.
2018年1月 五套装备各自前往前五个海外赛事地点
That January shipment sent the first five kits to the first five flyaway races
——澳大利亚墨尔本 巴林萨基尔 中国上海 阿塞拜疆巴库 加拿大蒙特利尔
—Melbourne, Australia; Sakhir, Bahrain; Shanghai, China; Baku, Azerbaijan; and Montreal, Canada.
在每场比赛结束之后 这些装备会重新打包送到下一个海外赛事地点
Then, as each race was completed
its kit was packed up and sent to the next flyaway race destination without a kit
——澳大利亚那套去新加坡 巴林那套去俄罗斯
—the Australian one went to Singapore, the Bahraini one to Russia,
中国那套去日本 阿塞拜疆那套去美国 加拿大那套去墨西哥
the Chinese one to Japan, the Azerbaijani one to the United States, and the Canadian one to Mexico,
然后到了赛季末 这些装备没有新赛场可去
and then towards the end of the season, when there are no more tracks to send kits to,
于是就运回各自车队的总部"过冬"
they're sent back to the teams' home bases for the winter.
在赛场上 F1车队的物流统筹组主要休息时间就是比赛进行的时候
At the racetrack, the Formula 1 logistics team's main downtime is actually during the race itself
但对于巴林到上海这段 物流统筹工作在巴林的周四之前就已经开始了
but for the Bahrain to China transfer real work began the Thursday before the race.
从那时起各个车队的物流统筹主管就开始制定收工方案
That's when each team's logistics manager started making their tear-down plan—
决定不同零件和设备以哪种顺序 装进哪个集装箱
deciding in which order and into which containers their different pieces of equipment should go.
当这些完成后 就可以坐等周末比赛结束了
Once that was completed there was really not a lot to do until Sunday.
在周日早上正赛开始之前 打包工作其实就已经开始了
On Sunday morning, before the race even started, the pack up began.
许多备件在正赛的时候用不上
Many of the spare parts can't be used during the race—
大奖赛中不会去换发动机
they're not going to replace an engine during the Grand Prix—
所以它们是第一个被打包走的
so they're the first pieces of kit to be packed into their containers.
比赛进行的时候打包工作可能不多 但结束后15分钟内打包便会开始
Not much happened during the race itself but within 15 minutes of it ending the main pack up began.
所有设备中最重要的赛车会进行赛后检查 保证其没有进行非法改装
The cars, the most important pieces of equipment,
were subjected to a post-race inspection to be sure no illegal modifications were made
而其他所有东西都会立即打包起来
but everything else was immediately ready for packing.
所有车队希望最先到达目的地的设备会放入三个优先包裹中
All the equipment that the teams wanted at the destination first were put in one of three priority pallets.
所有车队的所有优先包裹会率先登上去上海的第一架飞机
Together each team's priority pallets filled up the first plane to Shanghai.
比赛结束后几小时 当它们打包完成 就会立即被运往机场
As soon as these were packed they were driven directly to the airport only a few hours after the race ended
准备搭上明天一早飞往上海的飞机
to be prepared for an early morning flight to Shanghai.
当那架飞机起飞后 赛场上剩余所有东西也都打包完成
As that plane took off the final pallets were being packed up back at the racetrack.
在比赛结束仅仅六到八小时后
Only about six to eight hours after the drop of the checkered flag,
所有东西都整装待发前往机场了
all pallets were packed up and on their way to the airport.
在周一中午 所有6架运送车队设备的波音747都已起飞前往中国
By midday Monday, all six of the Boeing 747's used to transport the teams equipment to China were in the air.
这些飞机是由F1赛事方订的 但钱还是要由车队付
These planes were chartered by Formula 1 but the teams still pay for the space.
同时在周一 所有相关人员也启程前往上海
Also on Monday all the staff started their journey to Shanghai.
多数普通员工会乘坐一般的商业航班
Many of the lower level staff just flew on normal commercial flights
而一些高等级的车手则会坐私人飞机
while some of the higher profile drivers flew private between the two countries.
九小时的飞行后 第一架飞机在当地傍晚时分落地上海
After nine hours in the air the first plane touched down in Shanghai around early evening local time.
然后卸货交付
The freight was unloaded and brought to customs.
午夜时分 所有优先包裹都启程前往赛场
By midnight, all the priority freight was on its way to the racetrack.
当晚 负责统筹的工人会把不同车队的优先包裹安置在各自的位置
Overnight, logistics workers arranged the different teams' freight into their respective paddocks.
在所有车队的货物都抵达之前 任何车队都不许先碰自己的货物
No team is allowed to touch their freight until all the other teams' freight has arrived
一方面是为了公平 一方面是为了安全 让卸货时周围没有闲杂人员
both for fairness purposes and safety to assure that there aren't many people around
as pallets are being unloaded and moved.
在周二早上 组装组的人开始干活
By Tuesday morning, it's game on for the assembly crews.
此时每个车队手里有三个优先包裹和之前提到的海外装备
At this point each team had their three priority pallets and their sea kit.
在优先包裹中车队不会放最高价值或者最重要的货物
In their priority pallets teams didn't put the highest value or most important cargo,
而是放最先需要组装的设备——P房的框架
they put the things they needed to assemble first—the bare bones of their garage.
包括墙面面板 电子系统的核心部分 以及IT 通信的大部分设备
That includes the wall paneling, the core of their electrical system,
and the majority of the IT and communications equipment.
在周二晚上搭建完成后 赛道再次进行清场 不允许车队接近
By Tuesday evening that build was done and the track was once again made inaccessible to the teams
因为次优先包裹会在当天夜里抵达
as the non-priority pallets were delivered overnight.
周三早上大约六点 车队抵达赛场
Early Wednesday morning around 6am the teams arrived back at the track
开始P房的最后组装工作
and began work on the final assembly of the garage.
仅仅四小时后 当天上午晚些时候 所有车队的P房全部进入工作状态
Only after about four hours, by late morning, all the different teams garages were operational.
十支F1车队只用58小时就成功打包所有设备
All in all, ten Formula 1 teams successfully packed up,
运输到4000英里外的赛场并重新组装搭建完成
shipped all their equipment 4,000 miles, and reassembled their paddocks in 58 hours.
也多亏了精心的统筹工作与工人们的熟练技艺
Thanks to careful planning and practiced workers,
F1能在每年完美地完成如此壮举
Formula 1 pulls off this impressive feat every year without a hitch.